for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
（ダンゾウ）まさか
自分が返り咲くための謀略とは→
I don't want to believe that
he planned this
思いたくないが…。
so he could return to power...
（リン）カカシ　カカシ…。
Kakashi...
カカシ！
Kakashi!
（カカシ）はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
Hashirama's Cells
はぁ…。
（ガイ）あ～ん！
またシカトに戻ったか。
So he's back to ignoring me again.
Welcome!
((木遁　大樹林の術！))
Wood Style! Giant Forest Jutsu!
《木遁を使う
あの少年はいったい…》
Who is that boy
who uses the Wood Style?
Maybe I'll find some information there.
《あそこなら何かわかるかも…》
"HASHIRAMA CHRONICLES"
"FIRE STYLE"
《あった》
Found it.
《森の千手一族の長にして→
Senju Hashirama... The leader of
the Senju Clan of the Forest,
屍山血河なる世を平定せし男こそ
千手柱間であり→
brought peace and stability to
this bloody, war-torn world.
唯一無二の木遁忍術を
自在に操る》
He and he alone mastered
the Wood Style Ninjutsu...
《唯一無二の
木遁忍術のつかい手。
He and he alone mastered
the Wood Style Ninjutsu...
いや　もうひとりいる。
No, there's one more.
What does this mean?
どういうことだ？
How is he able to use
the Wood Style?
なぜ　アイツは木遁を使える？》
"TOP SECRET"
《極秘？》
Top secret?
中身はどこだ？
Where are the contents?
探しているのは　これか？
Is this what you are looking for?
プロフェッサー！
Professor!
構わん　わしが許可する。
読んでみなさい。
It's all right. I give you permission.
Read it.
は…。
Yes, sir!
かつて　初代火影　柱間様は→
Long ago, the First Hokage,
Hashirama-sama...
マダラとの死闘の末
木遁の術で九尾をおさえた。
after a death match with Madara...
used the Wood Style to
suppress the Nine Tails.
しかし　その後
木遁の術には後継者がいない。
After that, there was no one to
take over the Wood Style Jutsu...
尾獣をおさえるには
写輪眼か木遁が必要だ。
Either the Sharingan or
Wood Style are necessary
to suppress the Tailed Beasts.
木ノ葉隠れの里でも→
In the Hidden Leaf Village,
初代の木遁の術を
復活させようと→
there was a time when
they researched
里をあげて
研究した時代もあったのじゃ。
and tried to revive
the First's Wood Style Jutsu.
じゃが…。
However...
志願した大人たちに施した
柱間様の細胞移植の実験は→
despite the dedicated
efforts of many...
the tests to transplant Lord Hashirama's
cells failed one after another...
ことごとく失敗してしまい
犠牲者が増えた。
and the lives that were sacrificed
continued to grow.
そこで　残念ながら　その試みは…。
And so...
unfortunately, that jutsu...
was deemed a Forbidden Jutsu
and sealed away.
禁術として封印されてしまった。
ところがじゃ　近年
里の下忍　中忍→
But recently, genin and chunin,
果ては　暗部の者たちの中からも→
and even members of the Anbu
have gone missing.
行方不明者が続出している。
更に深刻なのは
木ノ葉の里周辺の村々から→
Furthermore, what's more disturbing
are incidents
where newborn infants
have been kidnapped
年端のいかぬ赤子が
誘拐されるという事件が→
from hamlets surrounding
the Hidden Leaf Village.
頻発しておることじゃ。
赤ん坊が！？
Infants?!
はっきりわかっているだけでも
すでに６０人になんなんとしている。
Of those confirmed,
there have been 60 kidnappings.
いったい…。
うむ…。
Who could have...?!
これから話すことは
ウワサに過ぎぬが→
What I'm about to tell you is hearsay...
禁じられておる
柱間様の細胞移植実験を→
Someone is continuing
the experiments
and trying to implant the cells
of Hashirama-sama.
続けておる者もいるというのだ。
ウワサだとしても　なぜそのような？
Even if they're rumors,
why would anyone...?
あらゆる術を
集めようとする者もいるだろう。
There are those who want to obtain
every jutsu that exists.
わしとて　もし
木遁をなせる術者がいればと→
Even I have wondered sometimes,
if there were only someone
who knows the Wood Style...
思うときもある。
Had that been the case,
さすれば　あたら四代目の命を→
the Fourth Hokage need not
have sacrificed his life.
犠牲にすることも
なかったろうにとな。
((それゆえ　四代目が→
Isn't that why the Fourth lost his life?
(命を失うことになったのでは
ないか？))
無論　すべては　ウワサに過ぎぬがな。
Mind you, this is just hearsay.
もし　柱間細胞を埋め込まれた
赤ん坊が実際いるとしたら？
If...
If Hashirama's cells had
really been implanted into infants...
赤子に細胞を埋め込むことなど
許されておらぬし→
Implanting cells into infants
is forbidden...
もし
誰かがそのようなことをしても→
And even if someone was doing so,
the possibility of it succeeding
would be very low.
成功する可能性は低い。
じゃが…
もし　いや　もしもの話だが→
However...
If... just if... the first infant who
was kidnapped survived...
最初に誘拐された赤子が
成長しておったら→
すでに　１０歳にもなっておろうか。
He or she would be
ten years old already.
１０歳…。
Ten years old...
揃ったか？
（みんな）はっ！
Are you all here?
Yes, sir!
明朝　寅の刻
三代目は護衛として→
Tomorrow morning at
the hour of the tiger,
the Third Hokage and five Anbu
under his direct command
直属の暗部５名のみを従え→
大名府に出立する。
will depart for
the Feudal Lord's prefecture.
四代目亡き今　三代目が
再び　火影に就任するためだ。
His purpose is to reassume
the Hokage post
left empty by the Fourth's demise.
これを許せば　木ノ葉隠れの里は→
If we allow this,
the Hidden Leaf Village will once again
be forced to accept
再び　弱腰で優柔不断な
頭をいただくことになる。
a weak and indecisive leader.
里のため
それだけは防がねばならぬ。
For the sake of the village,
we must prevent this at all cost.
そこで　お前たちの役目は→
Hence, your mission is...
その道中　すみやかに　三代目の
お命をちょうだいすることだ。
somewhere along the route...
take the life of the Third
quickly and discreetly.
ただし
何者にも知られてはならぬ。
Remember, no one must know of this.
あくまで　流れの忍の仕業に
見せねばならぬのだ。
It must appear that it was
the work of itinerant shinobi.
Understood?
よいな！
（みんな）ははっ！
– Yes, sir!
三代目様　ご用意は？
うむ。
Lord Third, are you ready?
Yes, let's depart!
出立じゃ。
敵襲！
Enemy attack!
木遁の術！
Wood Style Jutsu!
What?!
なに！？　うっ！
A Substitution?!
変わり身！？
木遁　大樹林の術！
Wood Style! Giant Forest Jutsu!
千鳥！
Chidori!
うわっ！
お前　木遁の術を　どこで覚えた？
You...
Where did you learn the Wood Style?
無論　素直に語るとは
思っていない。
I didn't expect an answer anyway...
行け。
Leave.
早く行け！
Go quickly!
That jutsu of yours will be critical for
the Hidden Leaf Village one day.
お前のその術は　いずれ
木ノ葉隠れの里に必要になる。
アイツらの標的は　三代目様のみ。
They were only
after Lord Third.
三代目様から　俺たちを
引き離すことが目的だったらしい。
It seems their purpose was
to separate us from the Third.
They scattered off somewhere.
どこかへ散っていったわ。
Were you all right here?
こちらは大丈夫だったか？
はい。
Yes...
Did you recognize the enemy?
敵の正体は？
I don't know who it was.
いえ　何者か正体はわかりません。
Well, that's all right.
まあ　いい。
あとは　三代目様が→
I'm sure Lord Third will take care
of the rest.
処理してくださるだろう。
悪いが　そのイスはまだ
余人に譲るわけにはいかん。
I regret to inform you...
that I won't be giving up
that seat just yet...
なぜ生きているのかとでも
言いたそうじゃな。
It seems like you want to ask me
why I'm still alive...
It's nothing like that!
いや…　今朝　大名府に→
I understood that
you left this morning
出立したと聞いていたからな。
for the Feudal Lord's prefecture.
A certain fellow betrayed me...
ある男が裏切って…。
Rather, he came back to me...
and warned us
いや　表返ってくれて→
大名府に向かう我々を
狙う者がいると→
that we would be targeted
on the way to the prefecture.
知らせてくれたのでな。
I can easily investigate and
find out who is behind this...
犯人は調べれば　すぐに知れよう。
And that person will be executed.
さすれば　その者が死罪になるのは
火を見るより明らか。
That is as clear as day...
しかし
これ以上　死体を増やすことは→
But it's against my principles
to cause any more death.
わしの主義に反する。
その者に会えるなら伝えたい。
If I could meet that person,
I would tell him...
That I will overlook his actions
this time...
このたびの行動に関しては
一切を不問に付す。
But in exchange,
he must do all that is in his power...
そのかわり
今後は木ノ葉隠れの里のため→
for the sake of Hidden Leaf Village.
力を尽くしてほしいとな。
相変わらずの平和主義だな。
You and your ideals of peace...
その甘さが　いつか
身を滅ぼすことになるぞ　ヒルゼン。
One day, that naiveté will be
the death of you, Hiruzen.
Hmm... perhaps you're right.
うむ　そうかもしれんな。
昔から　そうだった。
We've always been this way.
You are the light and
I am the darkness.
お前は光　俺は闇。
光あるところに必ず闇はできる。
Wherever there is light,
there is darkness.
But losing either one causes
disruptions in the world.
しかし　そのいずれかが欠けても→
世の中
うまくはいかんものなのじゃ。
プロフェッサー　俺は暗部にいる資格が
ありません。
Professor...
I'm unqualified to be in the Anbu.
なぜじゃ？
お前のおかげで命拾いをした。
Why? Thanks to you, I'm still alive.
Still, I nearly betrayed you once.
しかし
一度は裏切ろうとしました。
うむ。
I couldn't protect the Fourth...
わしは　四代目を守れなかった。
I can't blame you if
you hate me for that.
お前に恨まれても
しかたがないのう。
実は　生前のミナトに
相談されていたことがある。
Actually, when Minato was alive,
he came to speak to me about you.
((ミナト：少しでも　心の傷を
忘れることができるかと→
I wanted him to forget the pain
in his heart, even just a little...
That's why I assigned him
to the Anbu.
カカシを暗部に配置したのですが…。
But from the rumors I hear lately...
最近のカカシのウワサを聞くと→
I think I might have made
the pain go even deeper.
かえって　その傷を
広げてしまったのではと→
Right now, I regret it.
今では悔やんでいます。
心の傷を癒やすことは
誰にもできぬ。
No one can heal a wounded heart...
Only time can heal all wounds.
ただ　時間が忘れさせて
くれるだけじゃ。
Yes...
はい。
Well, there is one solution.
いや　１つだけ方法がある。
え？
Why don't you assign him
to guard Kushina?
クシナの護衛を命じてみては
どうじゃろう。
If he leaves his duties with Anbu
to watch over
暗部の任を離れ　人が命を育む姿を
見つめることで→
a woman who is about to
give birth to a new life,
perhaps it will trigger
a change in him.
何かが変わるかもしれん。
(はい))
You're right!
ミナトが亡くなったとき→
When Minato died...
I considered releasing you
from the Anbu, for a moment.
一度は暗部から
解放してやろうかとも思ったが→
But I am in need of your strength
at this time.
今のわしには
まだお前の力が必要なようじゃ。
Yes, sir!
はっ。
Will you continue on as an Anbu
who reports directly to me?
もう少し　火影直属の暗部として→
力を貸してはくれぬか。
Yes!
はい。
I hope that Minato will
forgive me as well...
ミナトも許してくれるといいのだが。
三代目様。
Lord Third...
There's something I need to tell you.
お伝えしておいたほうが
よろしいかと。
うむ？
Hmm?
There's someone in the Foundation
who uses the Wood Style...
根に木遁の術者が…。
やはりそうか。
Just as I thought...
I have an idea who it is.
Let me handle this.
だいたいは見当がついておる。
その件は
わしに任せてもらえぬか。
Yes, sir.
はい。
I see...
そうか　三代目が今一度
火影として立ってくれるか！
So you will be filling
the post again, Third!
You have the knowledge
and experience already...
知恵も経験もある。
それは安心だのう。
I am very relieved.
Is that man not here today?
本日は　あの者…。
The fierce-looking one
with that scary eye...
怖い目をした
強面の男はおらんのかえ？
Do you mean Danzo?
ダンゾウでございますか？
Oh yes, he's the one.
そうじゃ　そうじゃった。
He had an urgent matter to attend to,
so he is absent today.
ならば　急ぎの用件があり
欠席させていただいております。
Oh... I see.
ほう　そうか　そうか。
I don't feel very comfortable
around him.
余は　あやつが
ちょっと苦手じゃ。
We must cease direct contact
between us for the time being.
しばらくの間　直接
連絡し合うことはやめておこう。
Did something happen?
（大蛇丸）何があったの？
Kakashi betrayed me,
カカシの裏切りにより　我々のことが
ヒルゼンに伝わる可能性がある。
and there's a possibility
that Hiruzen knows about us.
That's not good.
それは　まずいわね。
In time, he might even learn
about this place and its secrets.
いずれ　ここの秘密も
バレてしまうかもしれない。
Well, we're dealing with the Third.
He'll be on to us eventually.
三代目のことだから
いずれ気がつくでしょうね。
No... He probably has already guessed.
いえ　すでに気づいているのかも。
Kakashi...
((カカシ…))
It won't wash off...
《落ちない》
Lord Third is reassuming
the title of Hokage...
三代目様が
火影に返り咲くらしいよ。
I thought the changing of
the guard would mean a new era...
世代交代で　ちょっとは
時代が変わるかと思ったのにな。
I know what you mean, Genma...
ゲンマの言うことも　わかるけどさ。
It's not going to be easy
for Lord Third, you know!
おい　三代目様だって
大変なんだぞ　あのお歳で。
Especially at his age!
We just have to do our best
for the village, that's all.
（アスマ）俺たちは
里のために頑張るだけさ。
Let's celebrate the return of
the Third Hokage with some dumplings!
（紅）さぁ　三代目の
火影就任を祝って→
お団子で乾杯しましょ！
– Yeah!
（みんな）おお～っ！
I-It's me! It's me, Kakashi!
お…　俺だ　俺だよ　カカシ！
You were seriously out
to get me just now!
すごい殺気だったぞ。
殺されるかと思った。
I thought I was going to get killed!
そっちこそ　何のつもりだ？
I should say the same.
What the hell were you thinking?
I was just...
俺は　ただ
ライバル対決をやらないかと→
I just wanted to lure you into
continuing our rivalry showdowns.
お前を誘おうと思っただけだ。
はぁ…　悪いな。
Sorry...
I already know
wakatten da yo
it doesn't belong to anyone else
hoka no dare demo nakute
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
kono sora ippai no niji wo kakete miseru yo
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
itsumade tattemo todokanai yo
I keep repeating the same thing every day
ato nankai mo kurikaesu nichijou
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
oikaketeru no wa itsuka jibun de egaita mirai
and I was blaming it all on someone else
mata dareka no sei ni shiteta
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I can't go on like this
kono mama ja dame na koto
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
kono me de midashita ashita no jibun wa mou shinjite ii n desu ka
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I have to go
ikanakucha ikenai koto
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
niji no mukou de matteru mou hitotsu no mirai he
The current emergency
summons is in place
こんばんは　氷川きよしです。
in order to promptly
recapture Orochimaru,
僕は今　愛知県
名古屋城の前に来ています。
who has slipped through our grasp.
The knowledge that Orochimaru holds is
a valuable asset to the Leaf.
それは　今回　「モクハチ」が名古屋から
お送りするからなんです。
If he leaves the Land of Fire,
it will be a fatal blow to the Leaf!
僕も出演しますので
ぜひ　ご覧ください。
When that time comes...
それでは 「モクハチ」　ｉｎ　名古屋　スタートです！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Rogue Ninja Orochimaru"
You... I like the look in your eye.